(自来也)入るぞ 綱手。
I'm coming in, Tsunade.
Jiraiya? Did you learn anything?
(綱手)自来也か。
何かわかったのか？
I discovered the whereabouts
of the Akatsuki leader.
暁のリーダーの
居場所をつかんだぞ。
What?! Is that true?!
なに!? 本当か!?
詳しく話せ。
Tell me more!
We'll use that information
to plan a surprise attack!
(シズネ)その情報をもとに
すぐに奇襲作戦をたてましょう。
Don't be hasty, now.
まぁまぁ そう焦るな。
This isn't like plotting
a sequel to your novel!
お前の小説の続編じゃ
あるまいし➡
We don't have the time to waste!
のんびりしてられるか！
Haste makes waste.
そう焦ると ろくなことはないぞ。
Especially with the stakes
this high...
特に 大事な賭けをするときはの。
どうだ？ 久しぶりに
二人っきりで➡
Say, why don't we grab
a drink together?
Just you and me.
外で 酒でも飲まないか？
I'll tell you everything there.
話は そこでしてやる。
You fool! I am the Hokage!
バカ！ 私は 火影だぞ！
昼間っから酒とはなんだ！
And you're asking me to go
drinking in broad daylight?!
Have you no shame when
our ninja are on duty?!
任務中の忍たちに
申し訳ないと思わないのか！
SAKE
BAR
ブワ～ッ！
お前…➡
You know...
You really ought to take your own words
a bit more to heart.
もう少し 自分の言葉に
責任もったほうがいいぞ。
Drinking sake straight out
of the bottle...
しかも 一升瓶をラッパ飲みとは➡
Remember, you are the Hokage, right?
仮にも 火影なんだしのぉ。
Twilight
That girl's late...
(水月)あの女 遅いねぇ。
How long does it take to
pick up supplies...?
買い出しに いつまでかかってる。
(香燐)
さっさと 夜にならねえかなぁ。
I wish it would get dark soon...
《重吾と水月が寝入ったら➡
After Jugo and Suigetsu turn in,
I'll make my move on Sasuke
while he sleeps!
寝込みのサスケを 襲ってやるぜ！
イヒヒヒ～》
興奮する～。
I'm so excited!
これは…。
This feeling...
(ナルト)キバ どうだ？
Well, Kiba?!
(キバ)集中して かすかな
サスケのニオイだけを追ってんだ！
I'm concentrating, trying to
single out Sasuke's faint scent!
So shut up! You're distracting me!
気が散るから 話しかけんな！
《間違いない…
ここに どんどん近づいてくる。
There's no mistake...
They're steadily approaching.
一つ 二つ…
チャクラも それなりの大きさ。
One...two...
Their chakra is strong too.
とにかく かなりの数だ》
There're quite a few.
《人のものじゃない
チャクラも感じる… 犬？
I sense non-human chakra too.
Dogs?
ニオイで追ってきているのか？
Are they tracking our scent?
Is it Akatsuki?
Or maybe the Hidden Leaf?
暁か… それとも
木ノ葉の追っ手か？》
INN OKOSHI
重吾 ボクは少し
香燐の様子を見てくるよ。
Jugo.
I'm gonna go check on Karin.
(重吾)あぁ。
Yeah.
な なんだ!?
Wh-What...?
Wake up, Sasuke!
起きろ！ サスケ！ 追っ手だ！
どうする!?
We're going to have company!
What do we do?!
Sasuke just waking up...is also nice!
《寝起きのサスケも… いい！》
We escape... Get ready.
(サスケ)逃げるぞ 準備しろ。
Jugo, mark every Akatsuki hideout
that we know.
重吾 お前は 地図に➡
わかっている 暁のアジトの場所を
すべて記しておけ。
(水月)もう いいのかい？ サスケ。
You're okay now, Sasuke?
Yeah. I've been healing a lot faster
since I absorbed Orochimaru's power.
あぁ。 大蛇丸の力を
取り込んでから➡
傷の治りが早い。
So this is the Power of the White Snake...
《これが 白蛇の力か…》
Whether it's Akatsuki
or the Hidden Leaf,
(香燐)暁にしろ 木ノ葉にしろ➡
イタチの情報を
持っているかもしれねえ。
they might have information
on Itachi.
だから 待ち伏せしたらどうだ？
サスケ。
So why don't we ambush them, Sasuke?
追っ手の人数が
お前の話どおりなら➡
From what you reported about
the number of people,
ソイツらは 十中八九
木ノ葉のヤツらだ。
it's most likely the Hidden Leaf.
暁は必ず ツーマンセルで動く。
Akatsuki always work
in two-man cells.
だとすると 待ち伏せしても
時間のムダになるね。
Which means an ambush
would be a waste of time.
Exactly. Forget the Hidden Leaf.
そういうことだ。
木ノ葉は 放っておけ。
Then what'll we do?
じゃあ どうするんだよ？
とにかく イタチだ。
イタチを見つけたら➡
Itachi is our only priority.
Once we locate him,
worse comes to worst,
最悪 木ノ葉は お前たちで止めろ。
you three must stop
the Hidden Leaf.
For now, team "Hebi" will use
the information gathered by Jugo
とりあえず オレたち蛇は
重吾が集めた情報に従い➡
暁のアジトを 手当たり次第に行く。
and check out Akatsuki hideouts
one by one.
わかったよ。
All right...
Let's go.
行くぞ。
少し 手伝ってくれ。
何だ？
Help me out for a second.
With that?
Can you gather as many birds
as you can?
小鳥を 集められるだけ
集めてくれねえかな？
何をする気だ？
What do you plan on doing?
前に着てた サスケの服だ。
This is Sasuke's old outfit.
It's soaked with his sweat
and smell, so we'll use this to...
汗の染みついた この服で…。
サスケが捨てた服を
なんでお前が持っている？
Why would you have an outfit
that Sasuke threw away?
うっ… そ それは
どうでもいいぞ。
Uh...! Th-That...
That's not important...
Y-You jerk!
…ハズだ！ この野郎！
と とにかく…。
A-Anyway...
《もったいねえけど…》
I hate to do this, but...
Sensory-Type Ninja have
different specialties
感知タイプの忍も 里によって
傾向があるのさ。
depending on their village.
木ノ葉は 探索に
犬の鼻を よく使う。
The Hidden Leaf often
use ninja hounds.
So we'll use that to
our advantage.
それを 逆手にとってやるんだよ。
あ!?
どうした？ キバ。
What's wrong, Kiba?
やばい！ サスケが移動し始めたぜ。
Shoot! Sasuke is starting to move!
急ぐってばよ！
サスケはイタチを追ってんだ。
Let's hurry!
Sasuke is going after Itachi!
ちょっと待て おかしいぞ。
Hold it, something's wrong!
サスケのニオイが分散してる。
Sasuke's scent is dispersing!
それも ものすごい数で
四方に散らばってんぞ！
Not only that,
it's scattering in all directions!
(カカシ)こっちの動きに気づいて
何らかの策をとったな。
He's on to us.
Taking strategic action.
On to us? But how?!
(サクラ)気づくって… どうやって!?
どんな能力か わからないが➡
I don't know what kind of power.
But I'm guessing he has
a skilled Sensory-Type Ninja on his side.
ま おそらく
かなり優れた感知タイプの忍が➡
向こうにもいるな。
(キバ)距離がありすぎる。
The distance is too great,
無線じゃ誘導できないぜ！
追えるのはオレだけ。
so I can't guide you
through the wireless.
I'm the only one
who can pursue him...
しかも ひとつのニオイだけだ。
どうする？
But it's one scent. What'll we do?
こうなったら
草の根分けても捜してやる！
I'll find him if I have to search
every blade of grass!
手当たり次第だってばよ！
With whatever means necessary!
多重影分身の術！
Multiple Shadow Clone Jutsu!
この先か…。
It's up ahead...
お前たちは命令するまで待機しろ。
オレが見てくる。
You guys wait until I give the order.
I'll go and see.
《誰だ？
Who's that...?
写輪眼！ サスケ!?》
Sharingan?!
Sasuke?!
《あ！ アイツは…》
Th-That's--!
Itachi...Uchiha!
《うちはイタチ！》
(イタチ)出てこい… うずまきナルト。
Come on out... Naruto Uzumaki.
オレを捕まえにきたのか？
You've come to capture me?
いや 違う。
No...I didn't.
I just came to talk to you.
ただ 少し話をしにきただけだ。
うわっ！
クッ！
そんなもん信用できるかってばよ。
Like I'd ever trust you!
《写輪眼を相手にするときは
１対１なら必ず逃げろ。
When up against the Sharingan,
if it's one on one, always run away.
２対１なら後ろをとれだったな。
If it's two against one,
get his back...
ただし コイツの場合➡
But in his case...
印を結んでからの
指の動きだけでも➡
Even while making a seal,
he can put his target under a genjutsu
using only finger movements...
ターゲットを幻術にはめる。
気をつけねえと》
I have to be careful!
お前が１人なのは知っている。
なぜ逃げない？
I know that you're alone.
So why don't you run?
フン！ オレの人数は
１人から1,000人までだぜ。
Hah! My numbers can go from
one to a thousand!
それに 逃げるわきゃねえだろ。
Besides, I can't run away!
お前を捕まえりゃ
サスケに会えんだからな。
If I capture you, I get to see Sasuke!
なぜ そこまで弟にこだわる？
アイツは抜け忍だろ。
Why are you so attached to my brother?
He's a Rogue Ninja.
少なくとも お前なんかより➡
That's because unlike you...
アイツのことを
兄弟だと思っているからだ。
I think of him as a brother
more than you ever would.
お前は すでに幻術の中だ。
You're already under my genjutsu.
クソッ！
Dammit!!
もう一度言う。
お前と少し話がしたいだけだ。
I'll say it again.
I just wanted to talk to you
for a moment.
で… その暁のリーダーってのは
雨隠れの里にいるんだな？
This Akatsuki leader is in
the Hidden Rain Village, correct?
うむ。
しかし あそこは
出入りする者に➡
Yes.
But that place conducts thorough checks
of anyone entering and exiting their territory,
入国審査と滞在期間中の監視を
徹底する国だ。
and they track
how long visitors stay.
合同中忍試験の手続きでさえ➡
Just preparing for the Joint
Chunin Exams is difficult each time
毎回 困難を極めるほど
厳格で閉鎖的な里だ。
because the village is
so closed off to others.
暁のリーダーが動き回れるような
里じゃないはずだがな。
Doesn't seem like a place where
the Akatsuki leader can move about freely.
だが… 厳格な里だからこそだな➡
However...because security is so strict,
自国の内情を
他国に知られぬよう➡
they're able to keep other nations
from learning about their internal affairs,
管理を徹底し
その恥を隠してきた。
and hence, keep a lid on any shame.
恥？
Shame?
あの国では どうやら
ずいぶん前から内戦が続き➡
It seems that land has seen
much internal strife,
里も二分されとるらしい。
and the village itself
has been split into two.
その一方の長が 暁のリーダーと
同一人物だという ウワサがある。
Word has it that the leader of one side
is also the leader of Akatsuki.
あの国は➡
That land is surrounded by
土 風 火の
三大国に囲まれ➡
EARTH
WIND                FIRE
the three great nations
of Earth, Wind and Fire.
昔から
それらの大国同士の➡
And from ages past,
it has been the battleground
of their conflicts.
戦場になることが
多かった。
そのため 内政も安定せず
難民ばかりが増えたらしいからな。
As a result, there has never been
domestic stability
and the number of refugees
is continually on the rise.
だからのぉ
とりあえず情報が確かかどうか➡
That is why I will infiltrate
and verify the information
we have gathered.
まず ワシが潜入して調べてくる。
作戦は それからだの。
Then we can plan strategy...
１人じゃ危険すぎる！
It's too dangerous to go alone!
ワシは木ノ葉の三忍だぞ！ お前も
その意味は知ってるだろう。
I am one of the Legendary Sannin
of the Leaf.
You know what that means as well.
悪いな…。
いつも損な役回りを押しつけて…。
I'm sorry...
that you always get
the short end of the stick.
ハハハハ！ 何だ急に…。
What's with you?!
火影になるべきは
本来 お前だったということだ。
I'm saying, you were
supposed to be Hokage.
三代目は
ずっと次の火影をお前に…。
The Third Hokage always wanted you
to be the next to--
I was never cut out for
that sort of thing.
ワシは そんな柄じゃない。
自由気ままが性に合っとる。
Being on my own suits me too well...
You regretted not being able
to stop Orochimaru.
大蛇丸を
止められなかったことを悔い➡
So all that time,
ずっと大蛇丸の動きを
１人で調べ回っていたのだろう。
you were tracking his movements alone,
isn't that right?
もう その必要もなくなった。
I no longer need to do so.
これで 小説の続編も
早く出せるってもんだ。
That means I get to release
the sequel to my novel sooner.
事実は小説より奇なりだなぁ。
まさか アイツが死ぬなんて…。
Fact is stranger than fiction, isn't it?
Who would have imagined that
Orochimaru would die...
昔 ３人で三代目のジジイに…。
Remember how the three of us would
go up against Old Man Third and...
あの まな板綱手が
今や巨乳の火影だ。
The flat-chested Tsunade has
become the big-bosomed Hokage!
Times are changing by the second.
時代は どんどん流れとる。
You were beautiful back then...
美しかったお前も 今や 50のババア。
死に別れた者たちへの思いが➡
and now, you're a
fifty-something old granny.
It pains me to see how all the memories
of your lost friends and loved ones
その大きな胸に
詰まってるかと思うと➡
are stored inside
that big breast of yours.
やりきれんのぉ。
しかし それは この先も増える。
And you know, the number
will continue to grow.
だが
しんみりするのは ちと違うのぉ。
I guess I shouldn't
wallow in sadness.
ワシの役目は 次の世代のために
手本となり 手助けをすること。
My duty is to be a model
for the next generation
and to help them.
そのためなら笑って命をかける。
For that, I'd happily give my life.
それが 年寄りのかっこよさ
というものだろうのぉ。
It's what makes us old folks cool, see?
ハァ… ハァ…
どういうことだってばよ？
Wh-What's going on?
お前は オレを狙ってたんだろ!?
だったら ここで…。
Aren't you after me?
Then this is your...!
もう行く。
I'm going now...
これから大事な用があるんでな。
I have an important task to do.
《影分身… 何だったんだ？》
Shadow Clone...
What was that?
(キバ)チッ… ここも外れだ！
Damn! This one's a bust too!
どうした？ ナルト。
What's wrong, Naruto?
Oh, nothing...
いや…。
何かあったのか？
ちょっと つまづいただけだ。
Did something happen?
I just tripped.
それよりキバ 次のニオイを追ってくれ。
Never mind that.
Kiba, track the next scent.
お前 ワシ以上に酒グセが悪いのぉ。
Your drinking habits are
worse than mine...
Want to stop and rest somewhere?
少し どっかで休むか？
It's late. We have to go home.
もう遅いから帰りますよ。
は～い。
- Okay!
Hey, wait up!
暁… あれほどの者たちを
まとめているヤツだ。
Akatsuki...
The leader is capable of organizing
a group so powerful...
どんだけ強いかわからんぞ。
Who knows how strong he may be?
それに わざわざ
敵の懐に入り込むようなもんだ。
You'll be walking right into
the enemy's territory.
さて… そろそろ行くかの。
Well then... I should set out.
Come back alive...
生きて帰ってこい。
お前にまで死なれたら… 私は…。
If I lost you too... I...
泣いてくれるのか？ 嬉しいのぉ。
You'll cry for me?
That'll make me happy!
But I doubt that it'll be
like the time Dan died.
でも
ダンのときほどじゃねえだろうのぉ。
バカが！
You idiot!
じゃあ お得意のギャンブルといこう。
Then how about making a bet with me?
お前は ワシが死ぬほうに賭けろ。
You bet that I will die.
お前の賭けは必ず外れるからのぉ。
After all, you always lose.
その代わり
ワシが生きて帰ってきたときは…。
But if I make it back alive...
なっ…。
ハハハハ！ 冗談だ 冗談！
Joking! I'm just joking!
お前には感謝してる。
You know, I'm grateful to you.
男は フラれて強くなる。
要するに そんなことは➡
Rejection makes a man stronger.
MAKE-OUT PARADISE
In other words,
you can't call yourself a real man
笑い話にするくらいの
度量がなけりゃ 男は務まらん。
unless you can laugh off stuff like that.
ネタにするくらいじゃないとのぉ。
Better yet, make a joke out it.
強くあるのが男の務めか？
So a man's duty is to be strong?
まぁの。
それに 幸せなんてのは➡
Kind of...
And besides... men aren't the only ones
who seek happiness.
男が求めるもんじゃないのぉ。
フン なに かっこつけてやがる。
女がいなけりゃ➡
Humph... Stop trying to act so cool.
Without a woman,
you guys can't be rejected.
フラれることもできねえくせに。
アハハ 確かに！
That's so true.
何かあったら
蝦蟇で連絡をよこせ。
If anything happens,
contact me through your toad.
私が すぐに駆けつける。
I'll rush over myself.
いらぬ世話だ。
お前は里を離れるな。
No need for that.
You must not leave here.
今は お前を頼りに
里が動いている。
The village relies on you now.
火影候補なら いくらでもいる。
There are other candidates
for Hokage.
コロコロと里長が変われば
里も安定しない。
There can be no stability
if the Hokage keeps changing.
お前以上の火影は
今 里には いないんだからのぉ。
Right now, you are the only one
who can be Hokage.
There's Kakashi.
カカシがいるだろう。
それに いずれは
あのナルトもいるしな。
And eventually, there's also Naruto...
フフフ… お前 やけに
ナルトを買っておるのぉ。
You're really sold on Naruto, aren't you?
まぁ わからんでもない。
Although, I can understand...
お前の弟 縄樹も
恋人だったダンも…。
Your kid brother Nawaki...
Your sweetheart Dan...
((３人 : 火影は オレの夢だから))
- It's my dream to become Hokage.
(自来也)そして ナルトも➡
And Naruto too...
同じ夢を追う
男たちっちゅうところかのぉ。
I guess you could say
they chased the same dream.
じゃがのぉ カカシはともかく➡
Sure, Kakashi can step in.
首飾りまでやってはいるが
ナルトは まだまだだ。
But Naruto still has a long way to go,
even though you gave him your necklace.
お前だって たいした
力の入れようだったじゃないか。
You have high hopes
for him too...
螺旋丸まで教えたくせに。
You taught him the Rasengan.
いや つい懐かしくてな。
Oh that... Well, call it nostalgia.
It reminded me of the days
when I taught Minato.
ミナトを教えた頃を思い出してのぉ。
波風ミナトか。 確かに似てるな。
Minato Namikaze...
True, Naruto does resemble him.
Minato was a genius that appears
only once in a generation.
ミナトは 10年に一度の逸材だ。
あれほどの天才は
もう生まれてこん。
There won't be another like him.
優しい男だったが
根性は筋金入り。
He was kind-hearted,
but had nerves of steel.
He rose to become
the Fourth Hokage so swiftly.
またたく間に四代目になった。
親になったことがないから
よくわからんが➡
I've never been a parent, so I don't know
much about these things...
アイツが ワシの子だったら
さぞかし鼻が高かったろうのぉ。
but if he had been my son,
I think I'd have been awfully proud.
フフフ そう言われれば
ナルトは そうも似てない気もするな。
Now that you mention it...
Naruto might not resemble him, after all.
ナルトは 自慢の息子というより➡
Rather than a son
you boast about,
手のかかる
やんちゃ坊主だからな。
he'd be the problem child,
always up to mischief.
どちらかといえば
あれは 母親似だからな。
Naruto is more like his mother...
たしか 元渦の国の くの一で。
Wasn't she a former kunoichi
from the Land of Eddies...?
あぁ 性格と忍術は
うずまきクシナそっくりだ。
Yeah... His personality and ninjutsu style
is just like Kushina Uzumaki.
おぉ そんな名だったなぁ！
Yes...that's her name!
赤毛で おしゃべりのおてんば。
That talkative, red-haired rascal...
She was such a tomboy.
まるで 男の子のようだったのぉ。
Kushina grew up to be a beauty,
but Naruto looks like his father.
I can see Naruto's father in him...
To me, it feels as though
I'm looking at my grandson.
It is being passed on...
the will of the Leaf,
from the past to the future.
I guess I'll be off.
Oh, that's right!
I had one last warning for you.
Huh?
Beware of the Foundation.
Yeah... I know.
Ah... Good then.
Farewell.
クシナも大人になって
美人になったが➡
Now, now, now!
Those from afar, listen carefully!
ナルトの顔は父親似だな。
Those up close, come and see!
だから ナルトには
アイツの面影が見える。
I am the super hot ninja
of the Leaf!
ワシからしたら 孫を見とるよう
とでも言おうかのぉ。
I can hear the wild cheers
of all the girls!
I may steal your hearts,
but they won't shatter!
受け継がれているんだな。
I help the weak and fight the strong!
過去から未来へと
木ノ葉の意志は…。
Now let the tale
of Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls begin!
Next time: "Tales of a Gutsy Ninja
~ Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls ~ Part 1"
TSUNADE'S ROOM
もう行くかのぉ。
Now then, today's guest is...
Hold it right there!
The most holy hermit sage
of the spirit of Mt. Myoboku Toads!
おぉ そうだ！
I am the great Master Jiraiya!
最後に ひとつ 忠告があった。
ん？
Oh, it's you.
What a greeting!
Aren't you happy to see me?
根の者には気をつけておけ。
Well, we don't have much to talk about.
あぁ わかっている。
うむ それならいい。
Don't say that. How about dwelling
into my heroic tales?
Heroic tales, huh...?
Yeah, something that'll make the women
watching their TV shout for joy.
じゃあの。